https://www.firstpresgreenville.org/privacy

Privacy
FirstPres HomePrivacy
Error
Privacy PolicyPosted April 3rd 2020The First Presbyterian Church (FPC) Website and Application are self-contained programs owned and operated by first Presbyterian Church of Greenville SC. We understand that The following statements will help you understand how we collect, use and protect the information you provide to us through our Website and Application.What we collect and How it is UsedInformation You ProvideWhen you use certain functions within the Website or Application, we ask you for personal information (such as your name, email address and an account password). We do not sell, rent, or disclose your personally identifiable information with outside organizations without your explicit permission. We may combine the information you submit under your account, with information from other FPC services or third parties to provide certain services, offer you a better experience and to improve the quality of our services. Examples of the above include, but are not limited to, providing online giving services, presenting you with spiritual development opportunities, adding new features, and analyzing our app or website performance. Within the Website and Application, you have the ability to give to FPC. Because we use third party services to process credit cards, we do not store full credit card numbers or verification numbers on our servers at any time.IP Address, Location Data and Device IdentifiersWhen you access the Website or Application, we may collect your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, location data, and/or device identifier. We use this information to provide a tailored experience for you, such as, but not limited to, helping you find and connect with nearby FPC locations. We also collect this information to determine the aggregate number of unique devices using our service or parts of our service, to track total usage, analyze data, and communicate with you more effectively. This information can include: the device operating system, hardware version, device settings, file and software names and types, battery and signal strength, and device identifiers, name of your mobile operator or internet service provider, browser type, language and time zone, mobile phone number and IP address. We may combine this information with information from third parties to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our service. We do not sell, rent, or share any personally identifiable information with third parties without your explicit permission.Website CookiesWhen you use the Website we may send one or more cookies to your computer, so that we may uniquely identify your browser. (A cookie is simply a tiny text file containing a string of characters.) Accepting our cookies allows you to keep your user preferences from session to session. Although most browsers accept cookies by default, you can set your browser to refuse all cookies, or to tell you when you are being sent a cookie. Some of the Website features and services may not function properly if you have cookies disabled.Log InformationWhen you use the Website or Application, our servers automatically record information sent by your browser or the application. These server logs may include information such as your web browser type, the API request, your IP address, browser type, application version, browser or device language, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies or identifiers that may uniquely identify your browser or device.User CommunicationPersonal information or requests that you submit through the Website or Application will be sent to the group administrator. The group administrator or one of their members will have access to this information. When you send email or other communication to us, we may retain those communications to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.Third Party SitesThis Privacy Policy applies only to the Website or Application operated by us. We cannot regulate other sites linked from within our various services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. You should familiarize yourself with their unique Privacy Policies, should you choose to visit their sites.How do we use your information?When you sign up for a particular service that requires registration, we ask you to provide personal information. We collect your information to support your participation, deliver requested content, to note your preferences, and to keep you informed about events, related resources, and spiritual development opportunities. You may opt out of electronically delivered communication at any time by using the unsubscribe feature for that service. You may decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case we may not be able to provide those services to you. As a visitor to our Website and user of our Application, you can engage in many activities without providing any personal information.How do we steward your information?We do not sell, rent, or share your personal information with other institutions without your explicit consent. We may share your personal information only if we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to: (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request; (b) enforce applicable Terms Of Use, including investigation of potential violations thereof; (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of us, our users or the public as required or permitted by law. We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data including internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. Unless explicit permission is obtained from you, we restrict access to personal information to our employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.Data IntegrityWe review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.Accessing and Updating Personal InformationWhen you use any of our services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate service purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup storage), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case, where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. The procedure to correct or remove your data will vary depending on the requested change. To request that your account be deleted, please contact contactus@firstpresgreenville.org.EnforcementWe periodically review our compliance with this Privacy Policy. When we receive formal written complaints regarding privacy issues, it is our policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between us and an individual.QuestionsAny questions about the privacy policy can be directed to: contactus@firstpresgreenville.org
